moosend.com 2019-04-27

# Read our GDPR Compliant Privacy Policy

**December 26th, 2017**

Moosend implements all appropriate measures to ensure that the information you provide to us remains private and secure as we seek to build strong and enduring customer relationships. Collectively so, Moosend Ltd. and/or any of its affiliates (hereinafter referred to as “Moosend”, “we”, “our”, “us”), in its capacity as data controller with regards to the processing of its direct clients’ personal data) and as data processors with regards to the provision of its Services to its clients, wishes to inform you in relation to the specific information we collect from our customers and how we use that information as part of our business activities. This Privacy Policy constitutes an annex to the Terms and Conditions for the Provision of Services. Capitalized terms used in the Terms shall have the same meaning in the present unless otherwise stated herein below.

## Questions & Concerns

Should you want to contact us about any concern or question you may have about your personal data and how we handle them, or if you want to change, delete, or change, any personal information that we hold, or you have any other question about any privacy and security matter please contact our data protection officer

Ioannis Stefanidis (Head of Finance)  
Data protection officer  
dpo@moosend.com  
Tallis house, 2 tallis street  
Ec4y 0ab, United Kingdom

## OUR COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

The personal information we maintain relating to you or other individuals may differ depending on our relationship, including the type of communications between us and the Services we provide. Moosend is cautious and explicit when requesting the information that is necessary for the successful provision of the Services. Such information may include:

**A. Personal information** (such as your name, physical address, email address and telephone number) which you provide to us by singing up and creating a personal access login for our email marketing products, or by contact our customer support team, send us an email, or communicating with us in any other way. We use that information to contact you regarding the provision of our Services.

**B. Invoicing information** (such as your Company name, Vat number, currency, telephone, invoicing address, town, country, postal code, IBAN,) that you provide to us when you choose to buy our paid services. We use such information to identify you, verify your purchase of our Services, and for invoicing purposes, as applicable.

**C. Email lists and end-user data**. When you add an emailing list to your account, we have and may access the data on that list only in purposes of providing services to you (such as support and customer care) and only upon your request and for the extend needed to provide these services. We store that data securely on our servers located in the EU/EEA and we do not sell, rent, or loan them to anyone. We are not responsible for the kind of personal data that you may include in your contact list or if these data were collected with an illegal way.

**D. Profile and demographic data**. We collect such data in order for them to be used to personalize our Services and display information on this web site and any requested email communications in a way that is more relevant to you.

**E. Marketing preferences** , or responses to voluntary customer satisfaction surveys (customer feedback). To improve our marketing communications, we may collect information about interaction with, and responses to, our marketing communications.

**F. Online activity information**. We may receive personal information about you when you use the Services or your activity when visiting our website; this may include your IP address, your operating system, your browser ID, your browsing activity and other online identifiers (to the extent that they are personal information), and other personal information that you provide to us online.

**G. Demographic and product use information;  **Moosend also compiles, in an aggregate form only, demographic and product use information. Moosend may, from time to time, opt to make such aggregate information publicly available. Under no circumstances will Moosend  make any personally identifiable information about an individual user available to anyone.

**H. Information about your use of our Services** : We may receive and store information about when and how you use our services and link them to other information’s we collect about you. This information may include for example, actions that you have taken when using our services, time, date). We use that information in order to act upon your support request and to improve our Services for both you and for all of our users.

## MINORS

Our Services are not intended for use by minors under the legal age requirement. No one under the legal age requirement may provide any personal information to or through our website while using the Services. We do not knowingly collect personal information from minors. If you are under the legal age requirement, please do not register with our website for the provision of our Services, make any use of the Services or send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number or email address. In the event that we find out that we have collected personal information from a minor without verification of parental consent, this information will be deleted. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a minor, please contact us at: [privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com)

To the maximum extent permitted by applicable law and without limiting any other provision of this Privacy Policy, Moosend disclaims any liability for any personal data submitted in contravention of this clause.

## HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use personal information to carry out our business activities and provide our Services. The purposes for which we use your personal information may differ based on our relationship, including the type of communications between us and the Services we provide.

The main purposes include using Personal Information to:

**– Authenticate you** when logging in to your account;

**– Communicate** with you and other individuals; We may communicate with you about your account and provide you with customer care and support when needed. We may also contact you in order to send you system alert messages such as planned outages, new or updated features, change in our legal terms, compliance and abuse warnings etc.

**– Assess your eligibility** for payment plans, process of payments and collect money owed to us; This may include for example sending you invoices, payment receipts, unpaid/overdue invoices, or alerting you about any other invoicing or payment issues.  
To check and enforce compliance with our Terms of Use. We may access data about the use of our Services in order to check if you comply with our Terms of Use and our Anti-spam policy.

**– Promote use of our services**. We may analyse data collected from the use of our service or visit to our website in order to promote our services to you. If you are visiting our site but you haven’t registered with our services we may contact you in order to give you more details about us, to invite you to sign up, or to inform you about any offers we may have at the time. If you are already using our services we may contact you in order to inform you about the use of another service we provide that we believe will benefit you. You can stop receiving our promotional emails anytime by clicking on the one click unsubscribe link included in every email we send. For more information see our “ _RECEIVING COMMUNICATIONS FROM MOOSEND_ ” section below.

**– Improve the quality of our Services** ; we may use aggregated data about the use of our services and visit to our website in order to improve our services. We may share this aggregated data with third parties (such us google analytics etc). We may also contact you in order to ask you to give as feedback about the quality of our services your satisfaction upon using them or any complaints or suggestions you may have that can help us improve the quality of the services that we offer.

**– Provide training and maintain information security** ; From time to time we may host or participate in events (webinars, seminars) in order to inform our users about important stuff such us (best usage of our services, best practices, data security, changes in legislation, important market related news that may affect them etc.) We may communicate with you in order to promote such events and to invite you to participate on them.

**– Prevent, detect and investigate crime** , including fraud and money laundering, and analyse and manage other commercial risks;  
carry out research and analysis, including analysis of our customer base and other individuals whose personal information we collect,

**– Carry out market researches** , including customer satisfaction surveys and assess the risks faced by our business;

**– Provide marketing information** in accordance with preferences you have disclosed to us about (marketing information may be relate to Services subject to your preferences);

**– Personalize  your experience** when you use the Services presenting information and advertisements tailored to you. We may contact you from time to time in order to provide you with suggestions for better use of our services, best industry practices, or new features that we may think that will help you promote your business and grow your audience ;

**– Manage our business operations and IT infrastructure** , in line with our internal policies and procedures, including those relating to finance and accounting, billing, IT systems operation, data and website hosting, data analytics, business continuity, records management, document and print management and auditing;

**– Manage complaints, feedback and queries** , and handle requests for data access or correction, or the exercise of other rights relating to personal information;

**– Comply with applicable laws and regulatory obligations** (including laws and regulations outside your country of residence), comply with legal processes and court orders and respond to requests from public and government authorities (including those outside your country of residence);

**– Establish and defend legal rights** to protect our business operations, and those of our group companies or business partners, and secure our rights, privacy, safety or property, and that of our group companies or business partners, you, or other individuals or third parties, to enforce our terms and conditions and pursue available remedies or limit our damages.

Moosend adheres to a permission-based email policy. For the collection and processing of your personal data we shall rely on your express consent. We may also collect and process your personal information based on any other legal bases that may be applicable, such as the performance of your contract with Moosend, the need for Moosend to comply with a legal obligation, the fulfillment of Moosend’s legitimate business interest, etc.

As our customer, your email address is only used to send information that you have requested. As required for the complete use of our email marketing software, we allow you to opt whether to receive or not, certain information from Moosend . Except as otherwise mentioned herein, Moosend  will not send unsolicited email information, commercial offers or advertisements to you. Moosend  will not sell, rent, or loan our contact lists or our customer’s contact lists (including customer data) to any third parties, nor will Moosend  use customer contact lists for our own marketing purposes. All opt-in emails we send in response to your request have an easy, one-click unsubscribe function for recipients. Unsubscribe requests are fulfilled without further communication being sent to requesting users.

## YOUR CUSTOMER DATA

### Creation of mailing lists

You can create and upload your own emailing lists by accessing your account with the unique email and password that you have selected. You are responsible for keeping your password confidential and for securing your login credentials from unauthorized use by a third party. You are also responsible for seeking proper consent according but not limited to GDPR terms & conditions from the end users in order to use their data and add them to your mailing list and for the kind of data that you decide to collect and upload. You can create you mailing list manually or import them automatically through many options that we provide (such as Excel, csv, Text, Copy paste etc.).

### Location of Storage

Your mailing Lists are stored securely on our servers located exclusively within the EU/EEA (Netherlands). We do not, under any circumstances transfer you mailing lists or any data about your subscribers and end-users outside the European Economic Area

### Security

Security and integrity of your data is our top priority. Thus, and in accordance with the GDPR regulation we take all necessary precautions in order to preserve both of them and protect your data against any other form of unlawful processing or disclosure to unauthorised persons. Part of these precautions include (ISO 27001 certification of our operating procedures, High end security facilities, levelling personnel access to personal and sensitive data, Sing NDAS with of all our employees and additional terms of data processing with personnel accessing sensitive data etc,). If you need more details about the security standards that we use please see our “THE SECURITY AND PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION” section.

### Accessing/Update/delete of your mailing lists

You can at any time access, update, export(download) or delete you own mailing lists.

## DATA SHARING AND TRANSFERS

We under no circumstances sell or share with others your end-user data. In connection with the purposes described above (see section above ‘How we use your personal information’), we may need to share specific personal information (Such as use/account identification information, Billing-payment and other financial related informations, services and site usage related info) with third parties. These third parties may include our group companies and external third party service providers (such as support and hosting service providers, banks and financial institutions that service our accounts, and other third party vendors and outsourced service providers that assist us in carrying out our business activities). We may also share personal information with government or other public authorities (including, but not limited to, courts, regulatory bodies, law enforcement agencies and tax authorities.

For the purposes noted above and during the applicable retention period, your personal information will only be transferred and processed within the EU/EEA. In the event your personal information is transferred outside the EU/EEA, Moosend undertakes the obligation to ensure that transfers to those countries will be made pursuant to the Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission or any other safeguards where permissible by the applicable data protection law. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites, services and applications (“Third Party Services”) that you opt to access through the Service or to individuals that we do not manage or employ. While we attempt to facilitate access only to those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot assume any responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access. If you need more info about our third party providers please send us an email at [privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com).

We or our partners also may use technologies (such as cookies) to collect information about your activities on our website or other sites in order to provide you with advertising based on your interests. For more information, you can check our cookie policy. To opt-out of third party cookies, please go to <https://www.aboutads.info/choices>.

## THE SECURITY AND PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Moosend’s own host servers in which processes and stores its databases are located within the EU/EEA (Secure facility in Netherlands). More info about the security of our servers can be provided to you in detail upon request on ([privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com)). Moosend uses appropriate technical, physical, legal and organizational measures, which comply with data protection laws to keep all personal information secure and to protect same against unauthorized and unlawful access and processing or accidental loss, destruction, damage, theft, use or disclosure.

As most of the personal information we hold is stored electronically we have implemented appropriate IT security measures to ensure this personal information is kept secure.

Moosend has deployed a sophisticated security architecture comprising the latest server, database, backup and firewall technologies to protect our information assets. All data resides in a tightly controlled, secure data center. That architecture ensures that information about the identity and preferences of our individual members is never accessible to anyone outside Moosend. We will maintain safeguards to protect the security of these Servers and your personally identifiable information. We also train our staff regularly on data protection and information security.

We do not store, access or process our customer credit card information. We use third party payment and subscription billing services for those purposes. We only use services that are PCI compliant and that maintain the highest security measures to protect your information. If you need more info about our third party providers please send us an email at [privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com).

Moosend accounts require that you log in with a username and password. Where we have given you or where you have chosen a password for access to the Services, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential and for securing your login credentials from unauthorized use by a third party. We request you not to share your password with anyone else. All account passwords are encrypted. We cannot see your password; we can only help you reset it.

All of our system-to-system communications as well as human to system communications for the purposes of customer support, analytics and email sending is done through secure, encrypted channels. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or electronic data storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any personal information you might have sent to us has been compromised), please immediately notify us at: [privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com)

Moosend   ensures that all subscriber lists, email content, and reports remain private and confidential. Moosend  may scan the content of your email campaigns to ensure they comply with our Terms of Use — for example, to protect against defamatory, inaccurate, abusive, obscene, profane, or threatening material that is racially or ethnically offensive. Moosend  will not sell, rent, loan, or invite external access to a customer’s contact lists. Moosend does not use its customer’s contact lists for it’s own purposes.

## HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will keep your personal information for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which we collect it and always in accordance with any applicable statutory data retention periods. The exact time period will depend on the purpose for which we hold your information but in no event this period will be longer than 12 months upon cancelation of your account.

## RECEIVING COMMUNICATIONS FROM MOOSEND

### Marketing Communications

You can change your marketing preferences at any time. If you wish to stop receiving marketing from us (“opt-out”), click on the “unsubscribe” link which is contained at the bottom all of our marketing emails, or contact us at: [privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com)  
We aim to comply with your opt-out requests within a reasonable time period and in any event within any period prescribed by the applicable legislation as each time in force.

Please note that if you do opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us, we may still send you other important service and administration communications relating to your account and the Services which we provide to you, and you cannot opt-out from these service and administration communications.

### Updates & Offers

After an initial email welcoming new users and verifying their new account and confirming their passwords and usernames, established users may receive occasional information on our company’s products, services, special deals, and recent news and events. Our customers are provided with the option to not receive these types of communications by using the unsubscribe function appearing at the bottom of each email.

### Service Alerts & Announcements

As required, Moosend  may email a service-related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily disrupted for any reason, we might send users an email. In general, users may not opt-out of these communications from us; however, their own email filters could block receipt. These communications are not promotional in nature.

### Customer Service

In accordance with the user’s option, we regularly respond to users’ service requests and account inquiries via email, or through live chat.

## WEBSITE USAGE

At times, we may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our hardware and software infrastructure, and to administer our website. These processes do not link your IP address to any personally identifiable information. We also use tracking information (such as cookies) to analyze user visits to different pages on our site.. This helps us design and operate a website that delivers the information you want.

## PRIVACY POLICY MODIFICATIONS

Our Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. If Moosend  does amend this Privacy Policy, we will post notice of the changes on our home page and send a respective email to all users. Those amendments will also be posted here, so visitors are encouraged to check back regularly for any changes.

## YOUR RIGHTS

Depending on your jurisdiction, you may have the following rights with regard to your personal information: (a) the right to access, (b) the right to rectification, (c) the right to erasure (right to be forgotten), (d) the right to request the restriction of processing (data minimization), (e) the right to data portability, (f) the right to object to the processing, (g) the right to withdraw your consent to the processing and (h) the right to file a complaint before the competent Data Protection Authority.

## YOUR CONSENT

By accepting this Privacy Policy and by granting your express consent, you accept the processing of your personal information, as set forth and for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

## CONTACT MOOSEND ABOUT THIS POLICY

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, the information we collect from you online, our practices on this site, or any other issue regarding your dealings with this website, or if you wish to exercise your rights, please contact us at:  
Moosend Ltd., 2 Tallis street, Tallis house, London, EC4Y 0AB, United Kingdom or email us at [privacy@moosend.com](mailto:privacy@moosend.com)

## QUESTIONS & CONCERNS

Should you want to contact us about any concern or question you may have about your personal data and how we handle them, or if you want to change, delete, or change, any personal information that we hold, or you have any other question about any privacy and security matter please contact our data protection officer

Ioannis Stefanidis (Head of Operations)  
Data protection officer  
dpo@moosend.com  
Tallis house, 2 tallis street  
Ec4y 0ab, United Kingdom
